# **Carlos Urbina**

Highly motivated computer science major at Virginia tech with the goal of obtaining an internship in the computer science field and gaining experience about career paths and opportunities for the future.

Blacksburg, VA 24060 (571) 279-4516 ucarlos@vt.edu LinkedIn:

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **VT Dept of Computer Science**, Blacksburg, VA — Teaching Assistant | Software Design and Data Structures

August 2022 - present

Support students by hosting office hours and lab sessions. Exemplify mastery over course subjects by teaching/assisting students.

# CAVA, Burke, VA— Team Member

June 2021 - August 2022 (seasonal)

### **Rubik's Cube Club**, Virginia Tech— Founder/President

August 2021 - present

# VTHacks Hackathon, Virginia Tech, VA— Developer

February 25-27, 2022

36 hour hackathon in which my teammates and I developed a personal training webapp called RoboTrainer that delivers customized workout programs. This project is highlighted on my LinkedIn.

## Academic Dean's List, Virginia Tech—Recipient

Fall 2020, Spring 2021, Fall 2021

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Virginia Tech,** Blacksburg, VA— Undergraduate Computer Science major

August 2020 - December 2023

3.92 University GPA / 4.00 In Major GPA

Class rank 7/163 (Major) 49/1232 (College of Engineering)

### **Robinson Secondary School**, Burke, VA— *Advanced Diploma*

Graduated June 2020

4.36 weighted GPA

#### **Personal Skills**

Working with a team, including on medium-scale software design projects.

Team productivity tools (Microsoft Teams, GitHub, Google Suite, Zoom)

Focused and diligent in achieving goals.

#### **Technical Skills**

Java, Python, C, MIPS, MATLAB, HTML, CSS, SQL, Linux OS

#### **Relevant Coursework**

Intro to Software Design

Software Design and Data Structures

Problem Solving in Computer Science

Science

Foundations of Engineering

Discrete Math

**Applied Combinatorics** 

Linear Algebra

Data Structures and

Algorithms

Computer Organization II

Professionalism in Computing

**Statistics for Engineers**